A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Friends and Services, Series H FA317
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Portraits
  - Portraits - John D. Rockefeller - Photos Given to Various People, 1916-1954 (Box 138, Folder 1042)
    Autographed and plain photos of John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to legations, banks, schools, etc. Lists of recipients. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson.
    133.3
  - Portraits - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Portraits - Distribution, 1917-1951 (Box 139, Folder 1043)
    Distribution of autographed and plain photos of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to institutions and individuals. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    133.9
  - Portraits - Dickenson Portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1944-1959 (Box 139, Folder 1044)
    Portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. painted at request of his sons.
  - Portraits - Dickenson Portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1942-1944, 1959 (Box 139, Folder 1044A)
  - Portraits - Charles Hopkinson (John D. Rockefeller, Jr.), 1927 (Box 139, Folder 1045)
    Portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. painted at request of officers of Rockefeller Institute for Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Portraits - Rockefeller Family - Dickenson, 1946-1952 (Box 139, Folder 1046)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. paid for portraits of sons in military uniform; gave portraits to the boys in 1949. Correspondents include S. E. Dickinson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    133.10
  - Portraits - Rockefeller Family - Dickenson, 1949 (Box 139, Folder 1046A)
  - Portraits of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby Rockefeller Milton Pardee Mauzé - F. O. Salisbury, 1949-1960 (Box 139, Folder 1047)
    Salisbury painted six portraits in 1947 - one each of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller and Abby Rockefeller Mauzé and four of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; loan of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. portraits to David Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller; distribution of copies made by Fred Wright. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. O. Salisbury.
    133.11
  - Portraits of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Abby Rockefeller Milton Pardee Mauzé - F. O. Salisbury, 1953-1962 (Box 139, Folder 1047A)
  - Portraits of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. Pardee - F. O. Salisbury, 1946-1952 (Box 139, Folder 1048)
  - Portraits of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. Pardee - F. O. Salisbury, 1948-1952 (Box 139, Folder 1048A)
  - Portraits - Salisbury - Wright Copies, 1948-1962 (Box 139, Folder 1049)
    Arrangement between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Wright for painting copies of Salisbury portraits; family's satisfaction with results; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gifts to Wright. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Fred W. Wright.
  - Portraits - Salisbury - Wright Copies, 1948, 1960 (Box 139, Folder 1049A)
  - Portraits - Salisbury - Wright Copies - Virginia Legislature Copy, 1960-1961 (Box 139, Folder 1050)
    Wright copy.
  - Portraits - Wright - Miscellaneous, 1949-1950 (Box 139, Folder 1051)
    Wright portrait of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on horse; portrait of John B. Trevor. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. W. Wright.
    133.12
  - Portraits - Wright - Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 139, Folder 1051A)
- Publicity
  - Publicity - General, 1905-1925; Folder 1 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1052)
    Interviews published; statements regarding War Work; newspaper comments on Rockefeller activities; relations with editors; requests for aid to publications. Appeals to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s sons; printed material on New York Mirror Youth Program. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ivy Lee, Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel.
    19
  - Publicity - General, 1925-1931; Folder 2 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1052A)
  - Publicity - General, 1929-1939; Folder 3 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1053)
  - Publicity - General, 1935-1940; Folder 4 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1054)
  - Publicity - General, 1940-1945; Folder 5 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1054A)
  - Publicity - General, 1940-1941; Folder 5 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1054B)
  - Publicity - General, 1945-1947; Folder 6 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1055)
  - Publicity - General, 1946-1947; Folder 6 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1055A)
  - Publicity - General, 1937-1948; Folder 7 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1056)
  - Publicity - General, 1948; Folder 7 of 9 (Box 140, Folder 1056A)
  - Publicity - General, 1949-1952; Folder 8 of 9 (Box 141, Folder 1057)
  - Publicity - General, 1949-1951; Folder 8 of 9 (Box 141, Folder 1057A)
  - Publicity - General, 1952-1961; Folder 9 of 9 (Box 141, Folder 1058)
  - Publicity - General, 1954-1961 (Box 141, Folder 1058A)
  - Publicity - Mr. Train's Article, 1923 (Box 141, Folder 1059)
    "John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Challenges Capital" - for Hearst publication.
  - Publicity - Bruce Barton, 1919-1922 (Box 141, Folder 1060)
    Requests for interviews.
  - Publicity - Industrial Control Reports, 1934-1938 (Box 141, Folder 1061)
    Anti New Deal.
  - Publicity - John McCarthy Article, 1943 (Box 141, Folder 1062)
    Laudatory biography of family.
  - Publicity - M. C. Speidel Chain, 1938-1941 (Box 141, Folder 1063)
    Friend of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity - George Santayana Autobiography, 1945-1953 (Box 141, Folder 1064)
  - Publicity - Reedy's Mirror - Chester Krum, 1919-1920 (Box 141, Folder 1065)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments to editor regarding article on Rockefeller Foundation written by Krum; Krum writes second review - very laudatory. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ivy Lee, Chester Krum.
  - Publicity - New York Mirror Youth Program, 1957 (Box 141, Folder 1066)
  - Publicity - American Magazine, 1931-1952 (Box 142, Folder 1067)
    Various proposed articles, interviews - declined by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include Ivy Lee.
    19A
  - Publicity - American Magazine - I. F. Marcosson Article, 1936-1938 (Box 142, Folder 1068)
    Wanted to do article on family Benefactions; Ivy Lee checked drafts; result criticized for its "popularization" - "Giving Away Millions" was final title.
  - Publicity - American Magazine - December 1928 Article (Box 142, Folder 1069)
    "Three Big Things I Learned From My Father"; writing; letters of congratulations to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity - Albany New York Journal, 1924 (Box 142, Folder 1070)
    Appeal to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for aid to Republican newspaper declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ivy Lee.
    19AL
  - Publicity - Air Affairs, Incorporated, 1944-1950 (Box 142, Folder 1071)
    Reports on proposed cultural and philosophical aviation publication; Laurance S. Rockefeller became trustee; Nelson A. Rockefeller contribution; memberships lists, printed reports. Laurance S. Rockefeller and other trustees resigned over disagreement with President Bill Partridge regarding finances; change of organization's name to American Society of Air Affairs. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, William Partridge, Bill Borden.
    19A1
    Open per KWR, 02/24/2005.
  - Publicity - Air Affairs, Incorporated - Laurance S. Rockefeller Contributions, 1944-1948 (Box 142, Folder 1072)
    Totalled over $2,000; lists of early contributors.
  - Publicity - American Viewpoint, Incorporated, 1952-1953 (Box 142, Folder 1073)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller declined to get involved with magazine dedicated to "the preservation and extension of the American philosophy of living." Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Samuel Eule.
    19A2
  - Publicity - Architectural Forum, 1958 (Box 142, Folder 1074)
    Article on "Rockefellers in Building"; newspaper clippings regarding article. Correspondents include Martha Dalrymple.
    19A3
  - Publicity - Chicago Tribune, 1915-1922 (Box 142, Folder 1075)
    Wheeler, Tribune reporter, accompanied John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to Colorado; maintenance of friendship, which ended when Wheeler appealed for gift to a college. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. N. Wheeler.
    19C
  - Publicity - Christian Herald, 1919-1923 (Box 142, Folder 1076)
    Requests that John D. Rockefeller, Jr. write article for magazine, serve on committees, etc. all declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19C3
  - Publicity - Christianity and Crisis, 1941-1961 (Box 142, Folder 1077)
    "Christian Journal of Opinion" fighting Protestant isolationists; Nelson A. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller 3rd made small contributions. Reprints of some articles. Correspondents include John C. Brown, Arthur W. Packard, Nelson A. Rockefeller.
    19C8
  - Publicity - Colliers Weekly, 1907-1952 (Box 142, Folder 1078)
    R. H. Davis article on Belgian Congo stated John D. Rockefeller, Jr. invested in rubber concern with King Leopold and Aldrich; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. denied it, magazine printed retraction. Requests for interviews declined. Writing of "My Father Never Said Don't"; proposed Quentin Reynolds story. A. P. Sloan's article "Big Business Must Help Our Colleges." Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., P. H. Davis, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, Ivy Lee, Frank Jamieson.
    19C9
  - Publicity - The Churchman Associates, 1941-1959 (Box 142, Folder 1079)
    Family declined involvement and invitations from magazine headed by Guy E. Shipler, highly controversial character accused of leftism. Various hysterical newspaper attack clippings. Correspondents include Guy Shipler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Harold Ickes.
    19C10
  - Publicity - The Churchman Associates, 1949 (Box 142, Folder 1079A)
  - Publicity - Christian Century, 1947-1961 (Box 142, Folder 1080)
    Supported ecumenical movement; had financial difficulties - Rockefellers declined to contribute.
    19C11
  - Publicity - Ebony Magazine, 1951-1954 (Box 143, Folder 1081)
    Declinations of requests for interviews, articles, etc. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Frank Jamieson.
    19E
  - Publicity - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1921-1959 (Box 143, Folder 1082)
    Information for encyclopedia's article on John D. Rockefeller, Sr. and family benefactions. Nelson A. Rockefeller invited to join Board of E.B. Films, Inc. but declined; David Rockefeller declined to write article; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. purchases of Encyclopedia Britannica publications. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, William Benton.
    19E1
  - Publicity - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1946-1961 (Box 143, Folder 1082A)
  - Publicity - The Independent and Weekly Review, 1918-1922 (Box 143, Folder 1083)
    Subscription; appeals for assistance declined. Correspondents include Ivy Lee, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19In
  - Publicity - Publications Research, Incorporated, 1941-1947 (Box 143, Folder 1084)
    Article on P.M. Mazagine, article from P.M. Magazine; no logical explanation.
    19P
  - Publicity - Protestant Digest, 1939-1947 (Box 143, Folder 1085)
    Combating racial and religious intolerance; newspaper attacks on editor Leslie for leftism, anti-Catholicism, etc. No family involvement. Correspondents include Kenneth Leslie.
    19P1
  - Publicity - Protestant Digest, 1941 (Box 143, Folder 1085A)
  - Publicity - Protestant World, 1949-1955 (Box 143, Folder 1086)
    All-denominational monthly aimed to promote "sense of community" among Protestants. David Rockefeller declined to join Board; family declined to contribute. Financial difficulties. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dr. Robert Searle, Dana S. Creel, Frank Jamieson.
    19P2
  - Publicity - Protestant World, 1949 (Box 143, Folder 1086A)
  - Publicity - United States News, 1936-1949; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 143, Folder 1087)
    Weekly newspaper, became a magazine in 1939. Thomas M. Debevoise's political opinions, ideas regarding influence of the press. Friendship of Nelson A. Rockefeller and David Lawrence. Declinations of appeals to participate in symposiums. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Lawrence, Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19U
  - Publicity - United States News, 1938-1946; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 143, Folder 1088)
  - Publicity - United States Daily, 1926-1935 (Box 144, Folder 1089)
    Daily aiming at class circulation rather than mass appeal. 1927 John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution of $100,000 to send paper to schools and city officials on three month free trial subscription. Bought bonds through Robert W. Gumbel. Declined 1932 request for aid. Paper became weekly, U.S. News. Nelson A. Rockefeller interest in David Lawrence. Correspondents include David Lawrence, Raymond B. Fosdick, Thomas B. Appleget, Robert W. Gumbel, Arthur W. Packard.
  - Publicity - United States Daily - Bond Subscription, 1928-1933 (Box 144, Folder 1090)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. bought bonds - no further financial aid.
  - Publicity - United States Daily - Material from Wood's Office, 1930-1932 (Box 144, Folder 1091)
    Regarding Spelman Fund support for Daily.
  - Publicity - United States Society - Uncle Sam's Diary, 1932-1933 (Box 144, Folder 1092)
    School paper's request for support declined. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, David Lawrence.
    19U1
  - Publicity - Writer's War Board, 1941-1946 (Box 144, Folder 1093)
    Wartime agency; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributed to support of magazine for Britain describing United States - gave $1,500 for three years. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Rex Stout.
    19W5
  - Publicity - Young America, 1940-1952 (Box 144, Folder 1094)
    Aimed to teach schoolchildren civic virtues, invited John D. Rockefeller 3rd to buy stock. John D. Rockefeller 3rd loaned $5,000, declined stock or increase in loan. Loan partially paid off. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Stuart Scheftel.
    19Y
  - Publicity - Young America - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Contributions, 1940-1947 (Box 144, Folder 1095)
  - Publicity - Acknowledgements to Editors, 1915-1920 (Box 144, Folder 1096)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. responses to favorable and unfavorable articles and editorials regarding the family. Inglis ideas on John D. Rockefeller, Sr. 1924-1926 birthday editorials. Comments on University of Wisconsin 1925 decision not to accept corporation gifts. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19.1
  - Publicity - Acknowledgements to Editors - Kate O'Hara, 1919-1920 (Box 144, Folder 1097)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. was misquoted on socialist, asked for correction, had never been interviewed on the matter.
  - Publicity - Letters to Newspapers, 1924 (Box 144, Folder 1098)
    Appreciation for friendly editorials, thanks for clippings sent to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity - Letters to Newspapers - Alabama-Georgia, 1923-1928 (Box 144, Folder 1099)
  - Publicity - Letters to Newspapers - Idaho-Kentucky, 1924-1927 (Box 144, Folder 1100)
  - Publicity - Letters to Newspapers - Massachusetts-Oregon, 1923-1929 (Box 144, Folder 1101)
  - Publicity - Letters to Newspapers - Pennsylvania-Wyoming, 1923-1925 (Box 144, Folder 1102)
  - Publicity - Letters to Newspapers, 1923-1941 (Box 145, Folder 1103)
  - Publicity - Baltimore Sun, 1919-1922 (Box 145, Folder 1104)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments to editor regarding editorial on John D. Rockefeller, Sr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19.1B
  - Publicity - Associated Press, 1930-1954 (Box 145, Folder 1105)
    Thanks for favorable articles; declinations of requests for interviews. Correspondence with South American Associated Press man, John Lear; article on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s sons. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, John Lear.
    19.1A2
  - Publicity - Associated Press - Saul Pett Article, 1955-1956 (Box 145, Folder 1106)
    Article on the brothers.
  - Publicity - Associated Press - John Lear, 1938-1940 (Box 145, Folder 1107)
  - Publicity - Forbes Magazine, 1916-1957 (Box 145, Folder 1108)
    Interview with John D. Rockefeller. Forbes' request to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. to buy magazine bonds declined. Thanks for friendly articles; true anecdotes about John D. Rockefeller, Jr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s anonymous quote regarding putting workers on Board of Directors in industry. Articles on John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Nelson A. Rockefeller articles in Forbes. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. appreciation of B. C. Forbes' work. Correspondents include B. C. Forbes, Starr J. Murphy, Ivy Lee, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19.1F3
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine, 1936-1958 (Box 145, Folder 1109)
    Requests for interviews; proposed articles; drafts of articles. Laurance S. Rockefeller and Nelson A. Rockefeller decline to join Forum of Executive Opinion. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur W. Packard, Guy Greer, Russell Davenport.
    19.1F4
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine - March 1955 Article, 1955-1956 (Box 145, Folder 1110)
    Article on brothers praised by John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine - March 1955 Article, 1955-1956 (Box 145, Folder 1110A)
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine - July 1936 Article (Box 145, Folder 1111)
    On John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s philanthropies.
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine - Round-Table, 1939-1941; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 146, Folder 1112)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller participated in Roundtable on Unemployment; preparation of report. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, R. L. Buell, Beardsley Ruml.
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine - Round-Table, 1939-1940; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 146, Folder 1112A)
  - Publicity - Fortune Magazine - Round-Table, 1939; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 146, Folder 1113)
  - Publicity - Holiday Magazine, 1957-1961 (Box 146, Folder 1114)
    Story on the family by William Manchester. Correspondents include F. A. Jamieson.
    19.1H
  - Publicity - Holiday Magazine - Letters Regarding Manchester Book, 1959 (Box 146, Folder 1115)
  - Publicity - National Magazine, 1910-1936 (Box 146, Folder 1116)
    Article on John D. Rockefeller; John D. Rockefeller-Chapple friendship; request to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. for material, aid in distributing some of his work, declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. W. Chapple.
    19.1N
  - Publicity - New York Evening Mail, 1917-1925 (Box 146, Folder 1117)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on editorial on gifts and on industrial representation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ivy Lee.
    19.1N4
  - Publicity - New York Sun-Herald, 1919-1950 (Box 146, Folder 1118)
    Thanks for friendly editorials; declinations of appeals for interviews. Correction of misstatement of fact. Correspondents include F. A. Munsey, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., William Dewart.
    19.1N6
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune, 1919-1955 (Box 146, Folder 1119)
    Thanks for friendly editorials; reprint of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s "Peace and Good Will in Industry," declinations of appeals for interviews. Brothers advised regarding investment in newspaper. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19.1N7
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune - Eugene Gleason Article, 1949-1952 (Box 146, Folder 1120)
    Article regarding Rockefeller activities in New York City.
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune - Fresh Air Fund, 1942-1961 (Box 146, Folder 1121)
    Summer camp for underprivileged New York City children received contributions from John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Rockefeller Institute, etc. Suggestions for additional Board Members; clippings; Laurance S. Rockefeller involvement. List of family contributions. Correspondents include Whitelaw Reid, Arthur Jones, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune - Fresh Air Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1935-1961 (Box 147, Folder 1122)
    Annual contributions by Mrs. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Frederick H. Lewis.
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune - Fresh Air Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1961 (Box 147, Folder 1122A)
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune - Fresh Air Fund - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1948-1961; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 147, Folder 1123)
    Declined involvement until 1959, when he joined Board of Directors - relation of camps to his conservation interests. Finances of Fund; annual reports; minutes. Real Estate transactions. Mr. and Mrs. Laurance S. Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller, F. H. Lewis.
  - Publicity - New York Herald Tribune - Fresh Air Fund - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1948-1961; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 147, Folder 1124)
  - Publicity - New York World Telegram and the New York Sun, 1950 (Box 147, Folder 1125)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's best wishes on merger of two papers. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    19.1N8
  - Publicity - New York Mirror, 1955-1962 (Box 147, Folder 1126)
    Invitations to participate in youth program committees declined.
    19.1N9
  - Publicity - New York Mirror, 1955 (Box 147, Folder 1126A)
  - Publicity - New York Mirror - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1940-1958 (Box 147, Folder 1127)
    Declines to join Youth Program committee.
  - Publicity - New York Mirror - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1955-1960 (Box 147, Folder 1128)
    Declines to join committee.
  - Publicity - Saturday Evening Post, 1921-1961 (Box 147, Folder 1129)
    Copy of A. W. Atwood, "The Rockefeller Fortune," and "Why Don't They Quit," Aaron Davis' "Responsibility of Wealth," and other articles. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. invitation to writer to discuss adverse view of Rockefeller Foundation. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. comments on editorials. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    19.1S1
  - Publicity - Saturday Evening Post - Joe Morris Article and Book, 1950-1955 (Box 147, Folder 1130)
    Series on the brothers, publication in book form; reviews; David Rockefeller's opinion of book. Lists of letters received.
  - Publicity - Saturday Evening Post - Joe Morris Article and Book, 1953 (Box 147, Folder 1130A)
  - Publicity - Saturday Evening Post - Fistere Article, 1935-1938 (Box 147, Folder 1131)
    Draft revisions on article on the brothers.
  - Publicity - Scientific American, 1946-1961 (Box 148, Folder 1132)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller invited to invest in proposed science magazine, declined. Sending of articles of interest. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller, F. A. Jamieson.
    19.1S2
  - Publicity - The Survey, 1915-1952 (Box 148, Folder 1133)
    Social welfare publication. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. help in article on Industrial Relations Commission hearings. Fitch's criticisms of company unions; his article on Colorado Fuel and Iron (CF&I). Publication of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. statement on labor policy. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declined to join board, contribute. Nelson A. Rockefeller contribution to The Americas fund; declined to join Survey Associates, Inc. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, John P. Fitch, Paul Kellogg.
    19.1S8
  - Publicity - Time and Life Magazines, 1928-1961 (Box 148, Folder 1134)